Teun Zengerink

Senior Software Engineer

Personal details

Location: Amsterdam, The Netherlands

Email address: <u>teun@cyberpeaks.nl</u> Phone number: +31 6 5471 6572

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/tzengerink/

GitHub: https://github.com/tzengerink/
Company: https://www.cyberpeaks.nl/
Personal: https://teun.zengerink.com/



Software engineer with multiple years of professional experience in different environments. Passionate about developing creative solutions that have an impact on its users and society. Motivated to guide organizations in implementing Agile/Scrum practices, mentor junior developers and improve engineering processes. Admired by peers for being reliable, critical, authentic, outspoken, opinionated and emphatic.

Developer Experience

Languages & Frameworks

TypeScript, JavaScript, React, Angular, Vue.js, Next.js, Redux, NestJS, RxJS, GraphQL, Material UI, Tailwind, Sass, Less, Jest, Playwright, Cypress, Node.js, Yarn, Vite, Webpack

Tools & Platforms	Design & Project Management
GitHub, GitLab, Azure DevOps, Kubernetes, Jenkins, Amazon Web Service, Microsoft Azure, Cloudflare	Scrum, Jira, Confluence, Trello, Figma, Adobe Photoshop





Work Experience

Senior Fullstack Developer

Nationale Nederlanden, September 2023 - February 2024

Migrate a customer facing portal application to a new technology stack.

- Setup of new technology stack and collaborate with UI/UX-designer to create an optimal end user experience for the portal application.
- Create a backend for the frontend to communicate with SAP data storage through a configurable API gateway.
- Tech used: TypeScript, React, NestJS, Next.js, Material UI, Node.js, NPM, Vite, Azure DevOps, Gitlab, Figma, Scrum

Senior Frontend Developer

MyWheels, March 2022 - July 2023

Creating new frontend functionalities for mobile app, website and back-office application.

- Introduce automated testing and stricter TypeScript compiler options to increase code quality, maintainability and reliability.
- Assist growing development team in introducing the Scrum philosophy to add more predictability in creation of valuable output.
- Tech used: TypeScript, React, React-Native, Next.js, Jest, GraphQL,
 Yarn, Webpack, Tailwind, GitLab, Jenkins, Jira, Figma, Scrum

Senior Frontend Developer

Rabobank (via Accenture), Augustus 2021 - February 2022

Developing user interfaces for the onboarding flows that provide a fluent experience for new customers in opening a bank account.

- Improve state management by introducing Redux to produce consistent application behavior, while also reducing code duplication.
- Implement stricter TypeScript compiler options to create stronger quarantees of program correctness and easier code collaboration.
- Tech used: TypeScript, Angular, Redux, RxJS, Sass, Yarn, Jest, Azure DevOps, Microsoft Azure, Jira, Scrum

Senior Frontend Developer

GrandVision (via Cygni), January 2021 - July 2021 Building a whitelabel frontend for use in a MACH architecture serving eCommerce sites for multiple operating companies (Pearl, EyeWish, VisionExpress and others).

- Coordinate with Product Owner and Business Analyst to validate requirements and define technical approach for its implementation.
- Mentor and assist (junior) frontend developers in the team.
- Tech used: TypeScript, React, Redux, Sass, GraphQL, Jest, Yarn,
 Next.js, Lerna, Webpack, GitHub, Microsoft Azure, Jira, Scrum

Photography Internship

Takeaway.com, February 2020 - July 2020



Product Owner

Usabilla, August 2018 - December 2019

Accountable for iOS and Android SDK as well as the React-Native, Cordova and Xamarin bridges for those SDKs.

- Revamped the user interface of the forms while thoroughly testing it to meet accessibility standards.
- Improved the flow for enriching feedback items by attaching screenshots and camera images.
- Made use of design sprints, customer journey maps, problem area definitions, personas, brainstorms and validation interviews.

Senior Fullstack Software Engineer

Usabilla, January 2016 - August 2018

Responsible for creating well architected and maintainable code that meets the described requirements and end user expectations.

- Collaborated closely with the Product Owner, UX/UI designers and other engineers.
- Mentored junior engineers and participated in discussions with designers to create the best overall experience.
- Tech used: TypeScript, JavaScript, React, Angular, Jest, Sass, Node.js, PHP, Python, Symfony, D3.js, AWS, Jira, Scrum

Fullstack Developer

TROI Studio, December 2010 - January 2016

Tech used: JavaScript, Angular, Less, Python, PHP, Flask, MySQL, AWS, Linux, Docker

Fullstack Developer

Studenten.net, January 2010 - December 2010

Tech used: JavaScript, jQuery, PHP, MySQL, .NET

Education

Bachelor Arts, Culture and Media

Rijksuniversiteit Groningen, September 2006 - June 2009

Bachelor Business Administration and Computer Science Hanzehogeschool Groningen, September 2002 - June 2006

Certification

Certified Kubernetes Application Developer

Cloud Native Computing Foundation, August 2021

Certified Scrum Master

Xebia, January 2017

